In 2001, I was a brand new, shiny doctor, planning to save the world.
2001年，我还是个初出茅庐， 踌躇满志的医生，盘算着拯救世界。
My first job was working for three months on a lung cancer unit.
我的第一份工作， 是在肺癌部门工作了三个月。
Nearly all of my patients were smokers or ex-smokers,
几乎所有我的病人都是吸烟者， 或有吸烟历史者，
and most of them had started smoking when they were children
大多数人在他们还是孩子时
or in their early teens.
就开始吸烟了。
And despite living in a beautiful, wealthy country,
尽管生活在美丽，富裕的国度，
with access to the most sophisticated medicines,
可以获取到最先进的医药，
nearly every single one of my patients died.
但他们当中几乎没有人 逃脱了死亡的命运。
Everyone knows tobacco is bad,
每个人都知道吸烟有害，
but when you see the impact firsthand, day-by-day,
但是你每天亲眼看到这种影响时，
it leaves a very deep impression.
还是会印象深刻的。
Ten years later, I'm a radiation oncologist,
十年前，我是放射肿瘤学家，
fully aware of the suffering caused by tobacco.
非常清楚吸烟造成的痛苦。
I'm sitting at the hospital cafeteria, having my first ever meeting
我坐在医院的餐厅，第一次与
with a representative from my superannuation fund.
我的养老基金代表会面。
It was thrilling, I'm sure you can imagine.
实在令人激动，我相信你能想象。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
He tells me I'm in the default option.
他告诉我，我选择了默认选项。
And I said, "Option? Does that mean there are other options?"
我说：“选项？还有其它选择？”
He looked at me, rolled his eyes, and said,
他看了看我，翻了下白眼说，
"Well, there is this one greenie option
“好吧，这是一个粗略的选项，
for people who have a problem with investing in mining, alcohol or tobacco."
（尤其）对那些对投资矿山，白酒或 烟草行业有意见的人来说。”
I said, "Did you just say tobacco?"
我说：“你刚刚是说烟草？”
He said, "Yes."
他答道：“没错。”
I said, "So, are you telling me I'm currently investing in tobacco?"
我说：“你是说，我现在 在投资烟草行业？”
And he said, "Oh, yes, everyone is."
他答复道：“没错，每个人都这样。”
When you invest in a company, you own part of that company.
当你投资一家公司时， 你就拥有了这个公司的一部分。
You want that company to grow and succeed and thrive.
你想要这个公司成长，成功并繁荣。
You want that company to attract new customers,
你想让公司获取新客户。
you want that company to sell more of its products.
你想让公司卖出尽可能多的产品。
And when it comes to tobacco,
说到烟草行业，
I couldn't think of anything that I wanted less.
我想不出有任何我想要的东西。
Now, I know you can only see one person standing here
现在，我知道你们只能 看到一个人站在这里，
on this big red dot, on this enormous stage.
在这个红色的，巨大的舞台上。
But instead, I would like you to imagine
然而，我想让你们想象一下，
that you're looking at seven million people
你今天看到的是700万人
crammed up here beside me today.
紧紧挨在我身旁。
Seven million people across the world have died as a result of tobacco
仅在过去一年，全球就有700万人
in the past year alone.
因为烟草而失去了生命。
Just imagine, if a brand new industry were launched today,
只需想一想， 假如一个新行业今天成立，
and by the end of next June,
到下年6月底时，
that industry's products had killed seven million people.
这个行业的产品就会杀死700万人。
Would any of us invest in that new, deadly industry?
我们有人会投资 这个新的致命行业吗？
Tobacco is one of the most pressing global issues of our time,
烟草是我们这个时代 最紧迫的全球议题之一，
and most of us are far more complicit in the problem than we may realize.
我们大部分人涉及到这个问题中的 程度远超我们的想象。
So, the super fund representative explained to me
于是，超级基金代表向我解释，
that tobacco companies would be found
烟草公司就存在于
in the international shares portion of my portfolio.
我投资的国际股票中。
So I asked him, "Well, which international shares do I have?"
于是我问他：“我有哪些国际股票？”
He got back to me two weeks later with this list:
两周后，他给我提供了一份名单：
my number one holding in international shares
我在国际股票中的第一大持股
was British American Tobacco.
来自英美烟草。
Number two, Imperial Tobacco.
第二个，帝国烟草。
Number four, Philip Morris.
第四个：菲利普·莫里斯烟草公司。
And number five, the Swedish Match company.
第四个：瑞典火柴公司。
Four of the top five companies were tobacco companies,
前5大公司中有4家是烟草公司，
my investments, an oncologist.
这是我的投资， 一个肿瘤学家的投资。
And then I realized it wasn't just me.
随后我意识到这样做的不仅仅是我，
It was all members of my super fund.
还包括我的超级基金的所有成员。
And then I realized it wasn't just my super fund, it was all of them.
接着我意识到不仅只有我的超级基金， 几乎所有养老基金都是。
And then I realized, it wasn't just superannuation funds,
再接着我意识到，不仅养老基金，
it was banks, insurers and fund managers.
银行，保险公司和基金管理者都有。
And then I realized it wasn't just Australia.
然后我意识到不仅限于澳大利亚。
It was the entire global finance sector,
全球金融行业都是如此，
completely tangled up with the tobacco industry.
与烟草业完全纠缠在一起。
The industry that makes products that kill seven million people every year.
这个行业的产品 每年导致700万人死亡。
So I started discussing the issue with my superannuation fund,
于是我开始与我的 养老基金团队讨论这个问题，
and I've been discussing it ever since.
从那以后我就一直在讨论这个问题。
Finance leaders have many challenging issues to deal with, these days.
今天，金融领导者们有许多 棘手问题需要处理。
So I suggest they adopt a framework
所以我建议他们 采用一个框架来清楚说明
that clearly articulates why it is reasonable
为什么投资如此多的烟草公司
to take a strong position on tobacco.
是合理的。
I suggest finance leaders ask a suite of three questions
我建议这些领导者们 用我的钱投资公司时，
of any company in which they might invest our money.
先问三个问题。
Question one:
问题1：
Can the product made by the company be used safely?
公司生产的产品是否可安全使用？
"No" is the answer for tobacco companies.
“不能”，显然是烟草公司的答案。
Zero is the only safe number of cigarettes for a human being.
对人类而言，无烟草是唯一安全的。
It could not be more black and white.
再没有比这个答案更黑白分明的了。
Question two:
问题2：
Is the problem caused by the company so significant on a global level
公司引发的问题在全球是否显著到
that it is subject to a UN treaty or convention?
需要受联合国条约或公约的约束？
"Yes" is the answer for tobacco.
对烟草行业，答案是“是的”。
Indeed there is a UN tobacco treaty
确实有一个联合国烟草条约，
that has been ratified by 180 countries.
并得到了180个国家的批准。
The treaty was created
条约之所以确立
because of the catastrophic global impact of tobacco.
是因为烟草带来了 灾难性的全球影响。
The current forecast is that the world is on track
目前的预测是，在本世纪内，
for one billion tobacco-related deaths this century.
全球将有10亿人死于与 烟草有关的因素。
One billion deaths.
10亿人死亡。
There's only seven billion of us.
地球上一共才70亿人。
Question three relates to the concept of engagement.
第三个问题，涉及到参与的概念。
Many financial organizations genuinely want to be good corporate citizens.
许多金融机构真诚希望 成为优秀企业公民。
They want to use their shareholder power
他们想要使用他们的股东权力
to sit down with companies, engage with them,
与公司一道，通过参与，
and encourage them to do better things.
鼓励公司做更好的事情。
So the question is:
所以问题在于：
Can engagement with the company be an effective lever for change?
与公司的接触 是否是改变的有效手段？
"No" is the answer for tobacco companies.
对烟草公司来说，答案是否定的。
Engagement with the tobacco industry is futile.
与烟草业的接触是徒劳的。
The only acceptable outcome would be
唯一可以接受的结果是
if tobacco companies ceased their primary business.
烟草公司停止他们的主营业务。
In fact, engagement with the tobacco industry
事实上，与烟草行业的接触
has never led to less human death.
从来没有降低死亡数字。
When we consider that framework, three simple questions,
如果我们考虑这个框架， 三个简单的问题，
we can see that is reasonable and defensible
我们可以看到，
to take a strong position and exclude investment in the tobacco industry.
排除对烟草业的投资 是合理的，站得住脚的。
In addition to the UN tobacco treaty,
事实上，除了联合国烟草公约，
there is, in fact, another global treaty that demands that we act on tobacco.
还有另一项全球条约 要求我们对烟草采取行动。
In 2015, the UN adopted the Sustainable Development Goals.
2015年，联合国通过了 《可持续发展目标》。
Now, we're talking about tobacco,
现在，谈到烟草业，
and I know you're going to jump straight to number three:
我知道你们都会直奔第三个目标：
good health and well-being.
健康和幸福。
And indeed, ramping up tobacco control regulation
确实，加强烟草控制
is essential if we're going to achieve that goal.
对于实现这个目标很关键。
However, look a bit more deeply,
然而，更深入一些，
and you will find that 13 of the 17 goals cannot be achieved
你会发现第13和第17个 目标也无法实现，
unless there is a major shake-up of the tobacco industry.
除非烟草行业发生了重大的变革。
Personally, my favorite goal is number 17:
我个人更青睐第17个目标：
partnerships for the goals.
促进目标实现的伙伴关系。
At present, we have the entire global health sector doing everything it can
现今，全球卫生部门 正在尽其所能，
to help the tidal wave of patients suffering as a result of tobacco.
帮助受烟草影响的患者。
But that said, in the past year alone, seven million people have died,
话虽如此，在过去一年， 700万的人还是因此失去了生命。
so clearly, that is not enough.
所以很明显，这还不够。
We also have governments aligned on tobacco, 180 of them,
各国政府也对烟草业采取了 共同行动，有180个国家参与其中，
busily trying to implement the provisions of the UN tobacco treaty.
忙着执行联合国烟草条约的规定。
But that, too, is not enough.
但那也远远不够。
If the global finance sector continues to lend money to tobacco companies,
如果全球金融部门 继续借钱给烟草公司，
to invest in tobacco companies,
投资烟草公司，
and to strive to profit from tobacco companies,
从烟草公司中赚取利润，
we are working against each other.
我们实际上就是在相互对抗。
Now, if we are going to disrupt
现在，如果我们要打败
what doctors call "the global tobacco epidemic,"
医生所说的“全球烟草流行病”，
we need every sector of society to stand side by side
我们就需要社会的 每个部门通力合作，
and be part of the solution.
成为解决问题的一部分。
So I call on finance leaders
所以，我呼吁金融领导者们
to implement a framework to deal with sensitive issues.
执行一个框架来处理这些敏感事项。
And I call on them to uphold global conventions.
我同时呼吁他们支持全球公约。
But in addition, there are business risks.
但除此之外，还存在商业风险。
Pure financial risks, associated with being invested in the tobacco industry
纯粹的财务风险， 与长期投资烟草行业
over the long term,
有关，
and I ask finance leaders to consider them.
我呼吁金融领导者们也要考虑这些。
The first risk is that fewer and fewer people will smoke,
首要风险是，随着烟草管制的增强，
as a result of increasing tobacco regulation.
吸烟的人会越来越少。
When these warnings were put on cigarette packets in Canada,
当这些警告被印在 加拿大香烟包装上时，
[Tobacco can make you impotent]
【吸烟会导致阳痿】
the first response of smokers was to give them right back to the salespeople
吸烟者的第一反应 是把烟还给销售人员，
and say, "Could you please just give me the ones that say they'll kill me?"
并说：“你能不能给我写着 吸烟致命的香烟。”
(Laughter)
（笑声）
Regulation gets noticed, regulation reduces consumption,
管制引起关注，管制减少消费，
and we have 180 countries committed to more regulation.
我们有180个国家同意增强管制。
Let's talk about litigation and the risk that presents.
让我们来谈谈诉讼及其带来的风险。
At present, it's the business model of the tobacco industry
当今，烟草行业的商业模式
that is being challenged.
备受挑战。
Currently, the tobacco industry externalizes all of the health costs
目前，烟草行业 将所有跟烟草相关的
associated with tobacco.
健康费用都外部化了。
Governments pay, communities pay, you pay, I pay.
政府买单，社区买单，你买单，我买单。
The tobacco industry externalizes all those costs,
烟草行业把这些锅甩得干干净净，
with an estimated one trillion US dollars per year.
据估计每年高达1万亿美元。
Yet they internalize and privatize the profits.
然而，他们却将利润 内化，私有化。
In 2015, in Quebec province,
2015年，魁北克省，
the courts determined that the tobacco industry
法院认定烟草业
was indeed responsible for those health costs,
确实要为这些健康成本买单，
and ordered them to pay 15 billion US dollars.
命令他们支付150亿美元。
That case is under appeal.
此案仍在上诉中。
But it begs the question, why should any of us, in any country,
但它引出了这个问题， 为什么我们所有人，所有国家，
be paying for the costs of the tobacco industry?
需要为烟草业的代价买单。
Let's move on to supply chain and the risk there.
让我们去看看供应链和其中的风险。
It is not well known
不为人所知的是，
that the tobacco industry significantly relies on child labor.
烟草业显著依赖童工。
In March 2017, the International Labour Organization
2017年3月，国际劳工组织
issued a report which stated:
发布了一份报告称：
"In tobacco-growing communities, child labor is rampant."
“在烟草种植的社区， 童工现象十分猖獗。
The US Department of Labor
美国劳工部门
currently lists 16 countries that use children to produce tobacco leaf.
现已列出了16个 使用童工生产烟叶的国家。
Scrutiny of supply chains is intensifying,
对供应链的审查力度正在增加，
and that cannot continue to escape public attention.
无法继续逃脱公众的视野。
Finally, there is also reputation risk to consider
最后，继续与烟草业
for individuals and organizations that continue to maintain an affiliation
保持关联的个人和组织，
with the tobacco industry.
还需要考虑声誉风险。
In countless surveys,
在无数的调查中，
the tobacco industry ranks as the world's least reputable industry.
烟草业都是世界上 最臭名昭著的行业。
Let's just look at the impact on children.
我们来看看对儿童的影响。
Globally, every single day,
全球范围内，每一天中，
it is estimated that 100,000 children start smoking.
据估计有10万名儿童开始吸烟。
That's enough children to fit inside the Melbourne Cricket Ground.
这个人数足够站满 墨尔本的板球场了。
And most of those children are from the poorest communities on earth.
这些儿童中的都来自 地球上最贫穷的社区。
Here in Australia, the average age that people start smoking
在澳大利亚，人们开始吸烟的
is 16 years and two months.
平均年龄是16岁2个月。
They look pretty young to me, but the worst thing here
他们看起来都非常年轻，但更糟的是
is that while we don't have data from every country on earth,
我们并没有全球每一个国家的数据，
we believe that is the oldest age.
而我们相信， 这已经算是最大年龄了。
Everywhere else is younger.
其他地方的数字都要更年轻。
Now for the good news.
现在说点好消息。
Things are changing.
事情正在发生变化。
The finance sector is coming to the party.
金融部门正在参与其中。
After around 2,000 meetings with finance leaders,
在与金融人士的2000多次会谈后，
primarily in the cafés of Melbourne and Sydney
主要是在墨尔本和悉尼的咖啡厅里，
and London and Paris and New York and all across the globe,
以及伦敦，巴黎，纽约和全球各地，
momentum, moving away from investment in the tobacco industry,
不投资烟草业的势头已经开始
is starting to snowball.
像滚雪一样蔓延开来。
Finance leaders are alarmed when they're presented with the facts,
当他们看到事实后，金融领袖警醒了，
and overwhelmingly, they want to be part of the solution.
大多数人都希望 参与到解决问题中来。
Here, in Australia, we now have
这里，在澳大利亚，我们现在有
10,636,101 superannuation accounts
10,636,101 个养老账户
that are tobacco-free.
不含任何烟草投资。
That one is mine, by the way.
顺便说一下，最后那个1是我的。
(Applause)
（鼓掌）
There is still a lot of work to be done,
仍然有很多工作要做，
but I've watched the conversation go from "Should we go tobacco-free?"
但我已经看到谈话的内容开始从 “我们不应该投资烟草业吗？”
to "Why haven't we done it yet?"
发展到“为什么还没开始做呢？”
In the past year alone,
单单在过去一年，
major tobacco-free moves have been made by leading financial organizations
已经有8个国家的主要金融组织
in eight different countries.
落实了无烟草运动。
In Australia, New Zealand, the Netherlands, Sweden,
它们是澳大利亚、新西兰、荷兰、瑞典，
Denmark, France, Ireland and the USA.
丹麦、法国、爱尔兰和美国。
By sovereign wealth funds, fund managers, pension funds,
包括主权财富基金， 基金经理，养老基金，
banks, insurers and reinsurers.
银行，保险公司和再保险公司。
Since tobacco-free portfolios began,
随着无烟组合开始以来，
more than six billion dollars has been redirected
超过60亿美元的资金
away from investment in the tobacco industry.
已经从投资烟草业抽离出来。
The case study is well and truly proven.
这个案例研究 已经很好地得到了证明。
When making the tobacco-free announcement in March this year,
在今年3月份宣告无烟组合声明时，
the CEO of AMP Capital said,
AMP资本的CEO说，
"We are not prepared to deliver investment returns
“我们不打算在任何 对社会造成损害的行业中
at any cost to society."
获取投资回报”。
And that is the question we need to ask ourselves.
这个问题我们也需要问问自己。
Is there no baseline standard below which we will not sink
我们赚取利润， 有没有一个不能触及的
to make profit?
底线？
Along the way, I've had a lot of help and incredible support.
在这个过程中，我得到了 很多帮助，和难以置信的支持。
Now, if you're trying to do something,
如果你想尝试做点事情，
I highly recommend that you have a princess on your team.
我隆重推荐，你的团队中要有位公主。
Her Royal Highness, Princess Dina Mired,
公主殿下，迪娜公主，
is the global ambassador for this work.
是这个工作的全球大使。
We also have a lord, a knight, a former premier,
我们也有一位领主， 一位骑士，一位前总理，
a former federal minister and a stack of CEOs.
一位前联邦部长和多位首席执行官。
But the capacity to change things
但是，改变事情的能量
does not rest exclusively with these highly influential people.
并不仅限于这些 具有高度影响力的人。
The power to do that is with all of us.
我们所有人都有能力做到这点。
Everyone here can be part of the solution.
这里的每个人都可以 成为解决问题的一部分。
In fact, everyone here must be part of the solution.
事实上，这里每个人都必须 成为解决问题的一部分。
Most people in this room own companies
这房间里的多数人都通过
via their superannuation funds, their banks and their insurers.
养老金、银行和保险机构 投资了一些公司。
And it is time for us to ask them:
是时候该问问这些机构：
Are they investing our money in companies that make products
他们有没有把我们的钱 投资到生产的产品
that kill seven million people every year?
每年会杀死700万人的公司去。
It's your money.
这是你的钱。
It's my money, it's our money.
这是我的钱，这是我们的钱。
And that is a very reasonable question.
这是一个非常合理的问题。
Pretty cramped up here,
这里非常拥挤，
with seven million people beside me today.
今天有700万人站在我旁边。
But if we don't act now, and act together,
如果我们不现在行动，共同行动，
we'll need to make way for one billion people
到本世纪末，我们就会让10亿人
before the end of this century.
白白送死。
And this is a very big stage.
这是个巨大的舞台，
But there is no more room.
但是已经没有更多的空间了。
Thank you.
谢谢。
(Applause)
（鼓掌）